Listing your first product is an exciting step in your seller journey.
To set yourself up for success, we recommend reviewing our pre-listing checklist before you get
started.
There are a few ways to list your first product, depending on your needs.
We encourage you to review and understand all your options, as you will likely want to list products
in different ways throughout your selling journey.
First, let's review the two basic types of product listings, existing and new.
Existing products are items that are already in the Amazon catalog.
When customers shop in the Amazon store, they are able to see all seller offers on a single product
detail page.
This helps customers find the products they want and compare offers and saves you from having to
recreate product detail pages.
When you list an existing product, you'll be adding your offer to an existing product detail page.
We refer to this as matching a listing.
New product listings are items that are not in the Amazon catalog yet.
When listing a new product, you'll need to fill out all the product information in addition to your
offer.
We refer to this as creating a listing.
When listing new products, your options will vary based on whether or not your product is branded.
And if that brand is enrolled in Amazon Brand Registry, in general.
If a product is part of a brand enrolled in Brand Registry, only three types of sellers can create
its product detail page using the standard listing process.
The original rights owner who enrolled the brand, other sellers verified as internal to the brand
and resellers authorized by the brand.
If a product is part of a brand not enrolled in Brand Registry, the product owner can create a listing
for it after they secure approval for their unregistered brand name.
Finally, if a product is generic, meaning it doesn't have a permanent brand name or logo affixed,
its listing can be created by the product owner using generic as a brand name during the listing
process.
In some cases, you may be required to complete a selling application for a product or category before
you can match or create a listing.
If necessary, you'll be prompted to complete that application during the listing process.
Whether you're matching or creating product listings, there are two ways to list your products,
one at a time or in bulk.
All sellers can list items one at a time.
That means you'll use a single product ID to match or create a listing.
All sellers can also match or create product variations one at a time.
If you have a professional selling plan, you can also match or create listings in bulk using a spreadsheet.
Step-by-step instructions for listing new or existing products one by one or in bulk can be found
in our comprehensive guide how to list your products on Seller University.